Credit where it's due, the format of this video is adapted from this brilliant wired playlist.
Hi, I'm John Abbas-Baki and I'm a developer advocate at Elastic.
In this video, I'll be covering various search algorithms and their applications in increasing levels of complexity.
Search is fundamental to how we interact with all information systems, but software especially.
Search engines like Google, Duck, Do, or Bing are probably the most common form of search we encounter on a daily basis,
but tons of other applications have search capabilities that you probably use all the time, like Netflix, Uber,
Wikipedia and LinkedIn.
Even when you're not directly searching for something, you still might be performing some kind of search in the background.
Many auto-complete systems are essentially a really fast search happening behind the scenes, looking for the word you're about to type.
Antivirus systems are constantly searching databases of malware signatures against the files on your computer.
Spam filters in your email inbox are doing something similar.
I could go on, but I think you get the idea.
Search is everywhere, and I'm going to walk you through the broad spectrum of search, starting from Level 1, LAMLINN.
So let's say you want to get into making pizza.
Your friend just so happens to own a cookbook all about pizza and lends it to you.
They tell you that the recipe on page 72 is a must try.
If you were to search for that page using a linear search technique, you could open up the
book to page one and then flip to page two and three and four and five, et cetera, until
you get to page 72.
Linear search is the most rudimentary way to look for something.
You, in a linear fashion, start at the beginning, check each page until you finally get to what
you're looking for.
It's not particularly fast or efficient, but it works.
Level 2. Binary Search.
So in the real world, you probably wouldn't start looking for a recipe on page 72 at the beginning of the book.
You know that these pages are in numeric order, and if there are roughly 130 pages,
you know that page 72 is towards the center of the book.
So you probably pop the book open to a page roughly in the middle, and maybe you overshoot a little
bit.
So you go back, and now maybe you undershoot.
And so you go forward a little bit, and then back.
and until you eventually end up on page 72.
A more precise version of what I just described is essentially how a lot of software does
search over any data that is ordered.
A book is always ordered by page count, so it fits nicely into our example here.
But what if the data is unordered?
Then linear search makes a bit more sense.
There's no reason to start looking for page 72 at the beginning of a book.
You know it's not there.
Whether or not your data is ordered or unordered is going to continue to be a key detail for every level
of complexity going forward.
Level three.
hash tables. If we wanted to know what page a particular chapter starts, you know that
you can open this book to the table of contents. You can check what page corresponds to what
chapters. That is, effectively, how a hash table works. I'm skipping over a lot of math,
but fundamentally a hash table works by creating a one-to-one mapping between two different sets
of information. Chapter 2, page 26. Different example. You drop off your coat at a co-check,
come back later that evening, and you give the attendant your ticket, let's say number 98. They know
exactly which coat is yours and where it is, all based on a number.
License plates, Social Security numbers, credit card numbers, any kind of unique ID is also
ultimately a one-to-one mapping between a number and information about a person in this case.
Level four, inverted indices.
If you want to find every recipe that has mushrooms in it, you know that you can open the
back of the book and find the index.
You now know exactly what pages have mentions of mushrooms.
A digital inverted index is the same thing as the index
in the back of a book, powered by the same math that hash tables use. In the context
of digital search, just imagine instead of indexing a couple hundred pages in a book, we're creating
an index for potentially billions of documents and millions of terms.
If you would implement the search feature in your favorite email system, an inverted
index would be a solid way to go. When a user searches their inbox for appointment, your email system
could check an inverted index against the term appointment and find every email that
has that word very easily. Level 5, TF and IDEA.
Okay, so now we're officially getting into the deep end. Everything up until now has had a clear
final destination. There was always a discrete exact answer to the question, where is page 72? From this
point forward, the answers to our search queries are not going to be so exact. Inverted indices get us part
of the way there by returning multiple results, but we may not want every mention of mushrooms
chronologically. Usually when we get back results from a search engine, they're ranked by what is
most relevant to our search query. Here's a more solid example. Say we tried the recipe of the recipe of
on page 72 and weren't a fan. So we head to the internet. And find a recipe website
and search for tasty artichoke pizza recipe. How does the search feature decide which
recipes to give us and in what order? Well, we can't rank any of the recipes without first
assigning them some kind of score. So we're going to need scoring functions. Any search feature
you use could be using a variety of different scoring functions, depending on the application,
but we're going to start with two of the most common scoring functions, the first of which is TF.
TF stands for term frequency and it is exactly what it sounds like. It measures the frequency of
our search terms in any given recipe. The more one of our search terms is mentioned in a recipe,
the higher the chance that it is relevant to our search query. Let's take a look at how
TF works by using it on two different recipes. Recipe A opens with a long blog post
about how the author was asked to make a cake for a friend's birthday. The author talks
extensively about the process of making the cake and the recipe at the bottom is ultimately for
cake. But artichoke pizza was served at this party, so gets a couple of mentions when they're
describing the birthday. So if we count the number of times the word tasty artichoke pizza
and recipe show up here, we get the following numbers. Now, let's look at recipe B. It's minimalist
and straight to the point. It's an artichoke pizza recipe, nothing more, nothing less. Again,
if we get the term frequency for this recipe, we get these numbers. If I gave you these numbers
and nothing else, which recipe would you guess was the better match for our search?
query. Again, you don't know that recipe A is for cake and recipe B is for pizza. All you see are
these term frequencies. Based on these numbers alone, our search system would assume that
recipe A is more relevant to our search query than recipe B. How can we fix this? IDF. The problem with
TF is that not all terms are created equal. In our original search query, the term tasty, is probably not
as important as the term pizza. IDF, or inverse document frequency, fixes this by measure
how rare a search term and your query is across all of the recipes and calculates
a score for that term based on its frequency. Let's look at how IDF works on the two recipes
we were looking at in the previous section. So these are the term frequencies for recipe A,
which we know is ultimately a recipe for cake, not artichoke pizza. What will the IDF
scores look like for these terms? Remember, the more common the term is across all the
recipes in our database, the lower its IDF score will be. Every recipe on this website probably has
the word recipe and tasting in it, so IDF will probably assign very low scores to those words.
They don't really help us narrow down what recipes we want. Similarly, words we would classify
as stop words like V and R with are equally as unhelpful and usually get assigned very low scores.
They show up all the time but aren't specific enough to really help us figure out what results to return
to a user. Conversely, the less common a term is, the more useful it will be for us, so we'll give it
a higher score. The term pizza is usually only going to show up in the rest of
recipes that are for pizza as opposed to sushi, pasta, bread, etc. Artichoke is easily the rarest
term in our search query showing up relatively and frequently in the recipe database. It will receive
the highest score out of all of our terms. So again, low frequency, high IDF score, high frequency,
low IDF score. A term's IDF score is inversely proportional to its frequency across an entire collection,
hence the scoring function is named inverse document frequency. For each term in the search
query, multiply its term frequency, TF, by its inverse document frequency, IDF, weight,
and add up all those values. And you get a score you can assign to each recipe. We can then rank the
recipes by these scores, and this way, we're able to generally get the most relevant recipes
up at the top and the least relevant recipes towards the bottom. By assigning very low IDF
scores to words like tasty and recipe, we're able to make sure that the recipe for artichoke
pizza comes out on top and the recipe for cake gets buried lower in the
search results. Level 6, BM25. Using TF and IDF together can make for a pretty
solid search algorithm all on its own, but it comes with some serious drawbacks. Let's look at two
artichoke pizza recipes. They're almost exactly the same, but one has some links at the bottom for other
artichoke-based recipes. That doesn't make it more relevant to our search query, but artichoke will
get a higher TF score in this recipe. The second major drawback to using TF and IDF together is
that it doesn't account for the total length of the document. Again, if I have two identical
artichoke pizza recipes, but one opens with a long post about the author's time in Italy and all the
pizzas they tried there, and the other recipe is just a recipe, the first one will be rewarded for all the
extra mentions of pizza it managed to include there. Best Match, version 25, or BM25, is a search
algorithm that uses both the TF and IDF scoring functions, but with some improvements to account
for these drawbacks. A saturation curve is applied to how term frequencies are calculated so that
mentioning pizza in your recipe one time versus two times significantly moves the score.
11 to 12, not so much. BM25 also takes document length into account and adjust the scores
accordingly. Overall, you can think of BM25 as a wrapper around the TF IDF combo that takes what
works and runs with it while also fixing what doesn't. Many search engines use BM25 as their default
algorithm. As of 2015, Lucene, of which Elastic Search is based on, switch to BM25 as
its default. Over a decade later, it's proving to be as reliable as ever. Level 7, text analysis. Up
until now, we've essentially just been performing keyword searches. When I ask for a tasty
artichoke pizza recipe with TF and IDF or BM25, I'm still just doing a control slash command
F on a large recipe database and ranking the recipes, albeit with an intelligent ranking system rather
than just seeing the results chronologically. A better way to search adds another level of
sophistication to what we search for, not just how we rank results. In order to achieve this, we need
to first break up our query through a process known as tokenization. In an effort to ease you into the
broad world of search, I've waited until now to explain something happening in the background that you
already have an implicit understanding of. Tokenization is the process of breaking down a query into
individual tokens that we can then further process. Before any scoring function like TF or I
can assign a value to a token, it first needs a token. There's no way to assign scores
to individual tokens in a query if you don't first extract those tokens. And I know the process of tokenization
sounds basic and probably not worth discussion, just extract words from a query separated by white
space. And sometimes it really is that easy. Other times you may need something more elaborate.
Should brick oven pizza be tokenized as brick oven pizza or brick oven pizza? If a user
types in how to make pizza. Should the pizza token include the question mark? What about
queries that look for recipes attributed to a specific person or restaurant? Should Danny's pizza be
tokenized as Danny pizza or Danny's pizza? I think you see where I'm going with this. There is no one way
to do tokenization. Luckily, you have options. Tokenization as a concept is platform agnostic. Any
search system is probably going to need some form of it. Elastic search ships with 15 built-in
You have tokenizers that work best with specific languages. Other tokenizers are adapted for
specific inputs like system paths or email addresses. Others let you leverage custom reg X. I could go on.
You can do a lot with tokenizers, but the basic idea remains the same. Take a query and break it down
into individual tokens. From here, we can perform further cleanup on our tokens in a couple of different
ways. Let's start with stopwords. I've already briefly talked about stopwords, but they bear mentioning again.
Stop words are essentially filler.
In English language, this includes words like the of and as are, you get the idea.
They're rarely helpful for our search queries, and for that reason, it's usually a good idea to just
filter them out. So something like pizza with broccoli will just get tokenized into
pizza broccoli. Synonyms. Whether I'm searching for New York-style pizza or NY-style pizza or NYC-style pizza
is totally irrelevant. The recipes I ultimately want are all the same regardless of which
of these queries I go with. So even if I type in NY style pizza, this recipe for New York
style pizza is still potentially a good fit. If we know we're going to encounter interchangeable terms
like this, we need to manually define these synonyms so that our search system knows to look for them.
That way, when I search for New York style pizza, I'm not just searching for New York,
but every other variation. Stemming. There are many variations of a single word depending on
its tense or plurality, but that usually isn't super relevant for our search. We really really
just care about capturing the stem form of the word. Essentially, its most basic representation.
So a query like charred, crispy crust pizza will get transformed to account for that. It doesn't
really matter to us that the word charred is in the past tense, so the search we're going to perform
will be using the word char. Whether a recipe describes its crust as crisp or crispy is
equally irrelevant. So we're going to transform crispy into its simpler form crisp. Spel
If I search for P-I-Z-A instead of pizza, I should still get the same results. Pretty
straightforward, and I'm sure you've seen this in your preferred search engine. How spell checkers work
can vary depending on the search system. In Elastic Search, we have a couple of different ways
of doing this. You could register incorrect spellings of words as synonyms. So P-I-Z-A becomes
a synonym of the word pizza. Alternatively, you could leverage Levenstein distance, which works by
counting the number of single-character changes between two words.
These changes include character additions, deletions, and substitutions.
So the Levinstein distance between P-I-Z-A and P-I-Z-Z-A is one because you only need to add a single
Z for the correction.
Separately, mozzarella, incorrectly spelled as such, has a Levenstein distance of two from its
correct spelling, since it's missing both a Z and an L.
Kirstie has a Levenstein distance of four from Krusty because the U and R need to be replaced,
a T needs to be removed, and the I.
needs to be replaced with a Y.
Using Levenstein distances, we can determine what words a user meant to write if they misspell it.
This is how fuzzy queries in Elastic Search work.
As the name implies, rather than only seeking out exact matches for tokens, you can get back
results that are within a Levinstein distance you specify.
Putting it all together.
When I search for the best wood-fired Neapolitan pie is what happens.
Well, my stopword filter will remove word number one, the.
Stemming will change fired to fire.
I know that pie is a synonym for pizza pie in this case, and spellcheck will correct the spelling to Neapolitan.
How it works.
I've already covered how spellcheck works under the hood, but stopwords, synonyms, and stemming are all handled
via a totally different mechanism in Elasticsearch analyzers.
These are pipelines that transform both the text in your search query and all of the data in your search database.
That last part might sound weird.
I know up until now I've only discussed transforming our search queries, but every document in
our search database also needs to go through the same analyzer.
So that means stopwords are removed, synonyms are identified, and words are broken down into
their stem form.
This should be fairly intuitive if you think about it.
In this example, I mentioned just a moment to go, we changed fired to its stem form fire.
That's all well and good, but it only makes sense if we change every recipe for Woodfired
pizza to Woodfire pizza as well.
Otherwise, we wouldn't get a match.
Level 8, re-rankers.
In an ideal world, our search system,
would work by having one person, let's say Reed Ranker, read every single recipe.
Then, when you search for a recipe, Reed would personally curate a list of recipes in response to your search query,
ranked from most relevant to least relevant.
Now, aside from how impractical it would be to ask Reed to read that many recipes,
it would also be incredibly slow for him to rank even a subset of recipes in response to your search query.
If we have thousands of pizza recipes on our site, it would take a very long time for him to rank
all of them. But you don't usually look at all the search results, do you?
Users tend to stick to the first couple of entries or pages return back to them.
So what if we kept all the infrastructure we've built so far, but gave some extra special attention
to the results we know our users will spend the most time with? We still have an inverted index
grabbing the subset of recipes that correspond to pizza, and we're still using BM25 to rank
all those recipes based on how well they match our search query. What we could do,
is just ask Reed to reorder the first page or two of our search results.
Now, unfortunately, Reed is only human. He wouldn't be able to rank even a fraction of the results
fast enough. But what if he trains a machine learning model to do the ranking for him? Machine learning.
For us to go any further, we need to explain machine learning, at least a little bit. I can't do a topic
this complex and broad real justice in a short video like this, but to the uninitiated, I will give you a
broad overview.
machine learning is exactly what it sounds like. It's how machines learn. The way this works is you
provide an obscene amount of data to what is known as a machine learning model. You can basically
think of it as a digital brain. If you provide this digital brain with millions, billions,
or trillions of data points, it can learn something very specific incredibly well. I can train a model
to tell apart images of pizza from images of pasta. And I can do this by providing as many
images as I can that I explicitly tell it are pizza and just as many that I tell it.
are pasta. I want to emphasize that I'm not telling it what makes these images different. I'm not
saying look for bread in one and spaghetti in the other or that pasta comes in these shapes and
pizza slices are either triangular or square. All I'm doing is giving it labeled data. Lots of labeled
data. The model figures out, on its own, what makes the two sets of images different. Hence machine learning.
The model will identify features in the individual images that it correlates with pizza and pasta
respectively. But we don't really understand what these features are. Rather than the intuitive
examples I gave earlier, like the shape of a dish, models don't see food. They see pixels. So the model
is identifying what arrangement of these little squares correlate with what dish. Models don't know
what shapes are or what anything is. All they have is the raw image data. Each time it sees a
picture of food, it tweaks the wiring in its brain a little bit. But we don't really understand this
wiring. If we did, we just program it ourselves and skip the training entirely.
This may sound weird, but it's not all that different compared to the way human brains work.
We understand the way individual neurons work and have a general understanding of the way the different regions in our brain work.
But as a whole, the human brain is a bit of a mystery to us.
With machine learning models, we may understand bits and pieces of the code inside, but the whole alludes us.
Okay, now that we have a basic understanding of machine learning, let's go back to our friend Reed.
Like I said before, he's only human and so can't rank recipes every time a user puts in a search query.
But he can train.
machine learning model on how to rank for him. If Reed is fed a steady stream of search queries
and an associated recipe, he can assign a relevant score to that pair. Let's say one equals this
recipe is a super bad match for this query and 10 means this is a super great match for this query.
If Reed does this for long enough, he will eventually have a great set of training data he can feed
into a machine learning model. But this isn't the only way Reed can generate training data.
Rather than giving a numerical score to each recipe, Reed could compare two random recipes and choose
which one is more relevant for a query. Reed could also just curate the top 10 most relevant
results in a ranked order for a query and feed that into the model. Or Reed could just use the
re-rankers that come out of the box with Elasticsearch. No training required. Regardless, once Reed
has a trained model, it will be able to very efficiently re-rank the top results before they are
displayed to the user. It pays for us to give these entries some extra attention since, like I said
before, most users will focus on these over whatever recipe is hanging out on page 24.
Level 9. Vectors. If we're going to efficiently use digital brains for search, we need a way to encode those digital thoughts.
For example, if a machine learning model needs to understand the concept of pizza, how does a computer wrap its head around that?
We talked earlier about teaching machine learning models how to differentiate between images of pizza and pasta, but the model still doesn't understand what pizza is, just what it looks like.
We also can't just feed it the dictionary definition of pizza. A model doesn't know what any of the words in the
definition mean. And if we fed it, the individual definition for those words, we'd need the definition
for those words and in those definitions and on and on and on and on and on. If we're trying to
represent an abstract concept, we need an equally abstract encoding mechanism. Enter
vectors, how AI understands concepts. Don't think of pizza in isolation, but instead as a broader part
of the typical menu options you'd find in say an Italian-American pizzeria or restaurant you'd find here in the
States. If you had to visually represent that variety to a computer, you would have something like
this. This is a gross over simplification of Italian-American cuisine, but it gets the point across.
To a computer, I can functionally break down all of these dishes into varying combinations of
cheese, dough, and tomato. Garlic knots are almost exclusively dough with a small sprinkle of
parmesan. Spaghetti and meatballs are almost equal parts dough and tomato. Again, with a small
sprinkle of parmesan. Pizza has all three of these elements, so it will sit close to the center.
Moncella sticks in isolation are essentially breaded cheese with no tomato whatsoever, so they'll hug the left side here.
You get the idea. We can make sense of abstract concepts if we can map them relative to one another.
But a computer is not going to have this visual to look through.
Instead, we will use a coordinate system to represent where these foods sit along the various axes.
There are some obvious catches to the way I've set this up, though.
For one, like I said, this is an oversimplification.
The dough axis conveniently ignores that pasta and bread are separate entities.
whether meat is a component of a dish isn't really factored in here.
Not to mention, I want my model to understand more than Italian-American dishes.
I want it to understand all food.
And I can't break down every cuisine in the known universe between three axes representing dough, cheese, and tomato.
And I also don't want to generate all these coordinates manually.
There's way too many different kinds of food out there.
This is a job for an embeddings model.
An embeddings model is a machine learning model whose sole job is to generate these coordinates for abstract concepts.
They're totally invented by the model.
Just like how we can train a model to differentiate pictures of food, we can train a model to approximate how related different concepts or things are, and it will graph them as it sees fit.
And the output is normally not along three axes, but hundreds or even thousands, depending on the breadth of data we're trying to encode in this vector space.
Nor do the axes come with nice human readable labels like dough and cheese.
Just like before, when differentiating images, we don't really know how the model is graphing or understanding things.
We just know it works.
Okay, so that was a lot of explaining vectoring.
and not a lot of how exactly that helps us with search. So let me fill in the gap.
Back in level seven, we talked about the importance of leveraging synonyms. For our purposes,
pizza is interchangeable with pie. Jargon like leopard spotting needs to be understood as charred crust.
It doesn't really matter whether we're going to use British English or American English,
making rocket and arugula or corgette and zucchini equivalent. In fact, it doesn't even really matter if we want to
throw in Italian words. Pomodoro and tomato are the same ingredient. Now, it's a lot of work to
manually define these synonyms, but we no longer have to do that. We can train an embeddings model
to generate embeddings for us, or just like with re-rankers, we can skip the training entirely and
use the out-of-the-box embeddings models elastic provides. We can then plot the coordinates in vector space
and intuit which terms are related or interchangeable. By measuring the distance between two concepts
in vector space, the model now understands what terms and concepts are and are not,
The closer two terms are in vector space, the more related they are. The farther they are, the
less related. Dogs and cats will be roughly in the same space in a vector database. Something
similar happens with how cars and trains are plotted, but a skunk won't be anywhere near the concept
of a skyscraper and a glove won't be close to a computer. Our search system can now understand
a broader spectrum of language. Level 10, hybrid search. As to be expected at this point,
using one strategy for our search systems usually isn't optimal.
inverted index helps us narrow things down, but it doesn't do any ranking on its own.
TF without IDF isn't very good. BM25 benefits from basic text analysis and doubly so for having
a re-ranker come in at the end and reorder the first couple of entries. We've strived to be additive so
far. We don't want to abandon the body of search strategies we've been accumulating in our toolbox
because no one method really does the job perfectly. So the national question is, how are we
going to incorporate vector search into what we have already discussed? Hybrid search is a combination of
BM25 keyword-based search and a vector-based search. Two different searches happen
simultaneously and then get merged together. There are many algorithms that can perform this smurge,
but the most popular would be reciprocal rank fusion, or RRF. How exactly it works is not the focus
of this video, so I'll spare you the math. What is more important for you to understand is why vector
search still often needs to be used in parallel with BM25. Vector search is great at finding recipes
similar to our search query, but BM25 still ranks supreme when it comes to finding
exact matches. Vector search will help me make the connection between cheesy flatbread and white
pizza, but BM25 is what will ultimately excel at finding recipes that are exactly cheesy flatbread.
And we haven't abandoned re-rankers either. Having one come in at the end and do a final pass-through of our
results is usually a good idea. Elasticsearch performs these types of hybrid searches exactly in the way
that I described. A standard keyword query is paired with a vector query,
and the results are subsequently merged.
You could make your life easier, though, and skip the need for both queries entirely by using a retriever,
a search option that runs multiple queries of different types for you, and merges their results into a single ranked list.
Level 11. Rag.
You are probably familiar with at least one LLM.
Whether it's Chatchip, T, Claude, or Gemini doesn't really matter.
They all work basically the same way.
A ton of data gets funneled into a machine learning model, and you now have a system that can talk intelligently to you about the data
that it ingested during its training phase.
LLMs are smart, no doubt about it, but in the same way that Isaac Newton couldn't have told you
who would win or take gold in the 1996 summer swimming Olympics, you can't ask an LLM for information
about knowledge it doesn't have, regardless of how smart it is.
So if an LLM ingested training data in 2023, but I wrote a pizza recipe in 2024, the LLM doesn't
have any way of giving anyone that recipe.
It wasn't in the training data.
And retraining is an exceptional.
expensive process. That's why new models don't come out every day. To fix this, we can augment
the generated output from an LLM with some sort of retrieval system to get more up-to-date data.
Hence the term, retrieval, augmented generation, or RAG. It essentially provides an open book to
LLMs so that they can look up information they don't have. To clarify, rag is not one specific
mechanism. It's just an umbrella term for any kind of tooling that lets your LLM perform some kind of look
or search. A good example of this is when you ask your favorite LLM about some current trends
like the newest recipes in the world of pizza making, so it starts crawling the internet. Elastic
Agent Builder is another example of Rag in action. It hooks up to whatever LLM you prefer, but
is also plugged into all the data we've loaded into the system. So if my Elastic instance is full of
pizza recipes, Agent Builder can crawl through those recipes and give me a specific one, rather
than just making one up based on its trading data.
Level 12. Agentic Memory. Not only are LLMs like ChatGBT using search to retrieve
up-to-date information for your queries, but search is also how it remembers you. LLMs don't
have infinite memory. They can only hold so much text in front of them at once. When a conversation
grows beyond that limit, or when a system is designed to remember you across multiple
conversations, the relevant parts of your history get stored and retrieved through search. If
Chatubt and I talk for a half hour about a recipe and I eventually say, never mind, let's
revisit that pickle pizza you recommended earlier. The system doesn't just remember that. It
searches for it. The LLM's memory, at its core, operates on search. Conclusion. Okay, that took us a while,
but hopefully you can see just how far we've come. We started this video with the most bare-bones,
brute force approach to search and ended with powering the memory systems behind AI. That's quite a leap.
The world of search engineering is broad and vast, and there's a lot of other algorithms I haven't
covered or have had to gloss over in this video.
PageRank is how Google Search operated for many years, but doesn't really have a place in the hierarchy of this video.
Nearest neighbor algorithms are super important for vector search, but are a little too involved for our broad scope today.
The same goes for string searching algorithms like Boyer Moore and Newth Morris Pratt, which are clever ways of scanning text for exact pattern matches.
More relevant to how search engines are built under the hood rather than how they rank results.
We'll continue covering different methods in search, but if there's something specific you'd like for us to go over, feel free to leave a comment on this
video. Until next time.